<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distributed Systems on Luke Olney</title>
    <link>https://lukeolney.me/tags/distributed-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distributed Systems on Luke Olney</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 21:36:29 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lukeolney.me/tags/distributed-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Urbit</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/readings/urbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 21:36:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/readings/urbit/</guid>
      <description>I found Urbit when somebody compared it to the &amp;ldquo;decentralized Internet&amp;rdquo; that Silicon Valley&amp;rsquo;s Pied Piper is building. It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s even more ambitious than that &amp;ndash; an attempt to rebuild the whole software stack from the Kernel up &amp;ndash; but this summary will focus on the network part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Roofnet Mesh Network</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/readings/roofnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 23:27:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/readings/roofnet/</guid>
      <description>Roofnet is a WiFi mesh network for increasing Internet access in urban areas. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be easy to set up: Users just need to place antennae on their roofs, and there&amp;rsquo;s no need surveys to determine the optimum place to put them &amp;ndash; since the network makes up the difference in performance. It does that, in part, though its routing protocol, which chooses routes that maximize bitrate and minimize loss-rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox&#39;s Distributed Storage System</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/readings/dropbox-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 01:24:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/readings/dropbox-storage/</guid>
      <description>Magic Pocket is Dropbox&amp;rsquo;s distributed storage system. It prioritizes simplicity, durability and availability, with a multi-level design that uses centralized coordination where possible. Data is replicated on all levels: between zones (which span an entire region, like the Eastern US) but also within each zone. The author notes in a HN comment the high-level similarities with GFS, which may warrant a closer look.
Below the level of zone is the cell, the largest storage unit with central coordination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPFS (Interplanetary File System) Proposal Paper</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/readings/ipfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 14:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/readings/ipfs/</guid>
      <description>IPFS is a distributed file system. It combines ideas from Kademlia, Bittorrent, Git,and Self-Certified Filesystems, taking respectively 1) routing and node identity, 2) block exchange, 3) Merkle tree-based verification and versioning, and 4) self-certification - addresses derived from public keys.
The result is something like a DHT that stores Git objects and uses the Bittorrent protocol for distribution. The certificate system, which does not rely on a trusted 3rd party to map addresses to public keys, is another major feature, allowing public-key encryption and ensuring that a malicious node can&amp;rsquo;t impersonate a node that has already established trust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>