<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Luke Olney</title>
    <link>https://lukeolney.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Luke Olney</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 02:21:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lukeolney.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrated Explantion for the Rotated Array Search Problem</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/posts/rotated-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 02:21:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/posts/rotated-search/</guid>
      <description>This is a detailed explanation of the &amp;ldquo;Search in Rotated Sorted Array&amp;rdquo; problem on Leetcode. The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t complicated, but because of the combinametrics involved, it has some nice symmetries that you might only see when you work out the problem fully.
In an ordinary binary search, the side of the array we choose next depends on how the target and the midpoint fall relative to each other. There are only two possibilities:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imputed Rent</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/posts/imputed-rent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 02:01:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/posts/imputed-rent/</guid>
      <description>https://mobile.nytimes.com/blogs/economix/2013/09/03/taxing-homeowners-as-if-they-were-landlords/?referer=
Imputed rent captures the idea that homeowners, as landlords, implicitly collect rent from themselves, as renters. Like ordinary rental income, then, it ought to be included in an account of the homeowners&amp;rsquo; income, even if it&amp;rsquo;s balanced out by an equally-sized expense. That would imply it&amp;rsquo;s only fair that income tax applies to this income, as well.
Although the concept is widely accepted, if imperfectly accounted for, in national income analysis - it&amp;rsquo;s used by the Deparment of Commerce in the calculation of GDP1 - scanning the comments of the linked NYTimes article reveals that the concept is deeply offensve to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My take on the Monty-Hall Problem</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/posts/monty-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 02:01:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/posts/monty-hall/</guid>
      <description>Monty-Hall is a simple problem that&amp;rsquo;s attracted a disproportionate amount of controversy. It&amp;rsquo;s originally formulated as follows:
 Suppose you&amp;rsquo;re on a game show, and you&amp;rsquo;re given the choice of three doors: Behind one door is a car; behind the others, goats. You pick a door, say No. 1, and the host, who knows what&amp;rsquo;s behind the doors, opens another door, say No. 3, which has a goat. He then says to you, &amp;ldquo;Do you want to pick door No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum Whitepaper</title>
      <link>https://lukeolney.me/posts/ethereum-whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 02:01:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukeolney.me/posts/ethereum-whitepaper/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/White-Paper#ethereum
People have come up with some creative purposes for the bitcoin blockchain, like metacoins, that weren&amp;rsquo;t anticipated in the original spec. Generally speaking, though, these applications don&amp;rsquo;t have the same security guarantees as bitcoin itself, and can&amp;rsquo;t leverage the network for anything more than storage. Ethereum expands on that idea, introducing a virtual machine and programming language with code that can be attached to every transaction. The result is that anyone can pay a fee to do useful work &amp;ndash; or store data &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s replicated on any node that keeps the full state of Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>